{"name": "63E  2006-4", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. For each of 3 years, the table below gives the number of our games a football team played, the number of running plays they ran, and the total number of yards the team gained on running plays.To  the nearest  tenth  of a  yard,  what  is  the  average number of yards gained per running play in 1998?", "choices": {"A": "2.6", "B": "2.7", "C": "3.6", "D": "4.9", "E": "5.1"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. For the polygon below, the lengths of 2 sides are not given. Each angle between adjacent sides measures 90\u00b0. What is the polygon's perimeter, in feet?", "choices": {"A": "41", "B": "52", "C": "60", "D": "140", "E": "200"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. Which of the following inequalities represents the graph  shown  below on  the real  number line?", "choices": {"A": "-2 \u2264 x \u2264 2", "B": "-2 \u2264 x \uff1c 3", "C": "0 \u2264 x \uff1c 3", "D": "2 \u2264 x \u2264 3", "E": "3 \u2264 x \u2264 -2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. What is the value of 3 \u00b7 2x+y  when x = 4 and y = -1 ?", "choices": {"A": "216", "B": "96", "C": "47", "D": "24", "E": "18"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. For integers a and b such that ab = 8, which of the following is NOT a possible value of a ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "1", "C": "-4", "D": "-6", "E": "-8"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. What is the volume, in cubic centimeters, of a cube whose edges each measure 4 centimeters in length?", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "16", "C": "24", "D": "64", "E": "96"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. A community center sponsored  a  1-day  craft  show. The center offered 2 sizes of display tables for rent and charged $40 to rent one of  the  70 large  tables  and $25 to rent one of the 50 small tables. Which of  the following expressions gives the  total amount of money, in dollars, collected from renting all of the small tables and L of the large tables?", "choices": {"A": "L + 50", "B": "40L + 1,250", "C": "40L + 2,000", "D": "65L", "E": "4,050L"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. In the figure below, A, B, and C  are  collinear,  the measure of \u2220ABD is 7x\u00b0, and the measure of \u2220CBD is 3x\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220ABD ?", "choices": {"A": "252\u00b0", "B": "126\u00b0", "C": "108\u00b0", "D": "54\u00b0", "E": "18\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Which of the following is NOT a possible value for a probability?", "choices": {"A": "0.001", "B": "0.5", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. For the first several months after the Fiery Red Scooter arrived in  toy stores,  the rate of  sales increased slowly. As this, new scooter caught on, however,  the rate  of sales increased rapidly. After several more months, many  people owned  a Fiery  Red  Scooter,  and the rate of sales  decreased,  Which  of the following  graphs could represent the total number of Fiery Red  Scooters sold as a function of time, in  months, after the scooter rived in toy stores? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. For a community service project, members of the junior class at San Carlos High School are going to varnish the rectangular dining room floor of a local nursing home.The floor is 60 feet wide and 80 feet long. Under the assumption that 1 can of varnish covers exactly 250 square feet, what is the minimum number of cans of varnish they will need in order to put 1 coat of varnish on this floor?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "9", "C": "10", "D": "19", "E": "20"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. Carl is making a scale drawing of his rectangular bedroom floor.The floor is 12 feet wide by 14 feet long. He is using a scale of inch = 1 foot for the scale drawing of the floor. What will be the dimensions, in inches, of Carl's bedroom floor in the scale drawing?", "choices": {"A": "3 by ", "B": "4 by ", "C": "6 by 7", "D": "36 by 42", "E": "48 by 56"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. According to a recent survey of students about the juice they each preferred, 20% of the students preferred cranberry juice, 40% preferred orange juice, 20% preferred grapefruit juice, and the remaining  students  preferred tomato juice. If each student preferred only 1 juice and 250 students preferred tomato juice, how many students were surveyed?", "choices": {"A": "330", "B": "500", "C": "625", "D": "1,000", "E": "1,250"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. The circumference of each tire on a bicycle is 50 inches. About how many revolutions does one of these bicycle tires make traveling 300 feet (3,600 inches) without slipping?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "18", "C": "72", "D": "300", "E": "864"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. (4x2 - 3x + 7) - (-1 + 5x + 2x2) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "2x2 - 8x + 8 ", "B": "2x2 + 2x + 8", "C": "2x4 + 2x2  + 6 ", "D": "6x2 - 8x + 6", "E": "6x4 - 8x2 + 6"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. A ticket for a movie at the Hazelnut Cinema costs $5.00. Latoya treats her younger brother to a movie at the Hazelnut Cinema. She gives him the money she brought with her, for his ticket and a snack. When he ask to play a video game, she gives him $1.00. That leaves Latoya exactly enough money to buy her own ticket. How much money did Latoya bring with her?", "choices": {"A": " $10.00", "B": "$11.00", "C": "$12.00", "D": "$13.00", "E": "$14.00"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. Mr. Gomez gave his class a test on 20 spelling words. Only one of the following percents is possible as the percent of the 20 words a student spelled correctly. Which one is it?", "choices": {"A": "77%", "B": "85%", "C": "88%", "D": "96%", "E": "99%"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. The first 5 terms of a geometric sequence are 0.375, -1.5, 6, -24, and 96. What is the 6th term?", "choices": {"A": "-384", "B": "-126", "C": "-66", "D": "126", "E": "384"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. (2x -3y)2 is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "4x2 - 12xy + 9y2", "B": "4x2 - 10xy + 9y2", "C": "4x2 - 9y2", "D": "4x2 + 9y2", "E": "4x - 6y"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. As shown in the figure below, Mr. Thompson, who is standing at point A, needs to determine the distance from point C on the ground to point E at the top of one of the second-story windows of his house.He places a  mirror on the ground at point B so that when he looks in the mirror, he can see the top of the window. Mr.Thompson's eye level, at point D, is 6 ft above the ground. He notes that AB = 4 ft and BC = 14 ft. Approximately how many feet above the ground is the top of the second-story window?(Note: In \u25b3ABD and \u25b3CBE, \u2220ABD is congruent to \u2220CBE.)", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "10", "C": "16", "D": "21", "E": "24"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. What is the solution to the equation 7x - (x - 3) = 6 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "-2", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "2"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. The area of \u25b3XYZ below is 32 square inches. If XZ is 8 inches long, how long is altitude YW, in inches?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "8", "C": "6", "D": "4", "E": "2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Given f(x) = 2x2 - 5x + 7, what is the value of f(-10) ?", "choices": {"A": "-243", "B": "-143", "C": "157", "D": "257", "E": "457"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. The cheerleading squad wants to to purchase new uniforms wear at the regional championship competition. They decide to sell candy bars for $1.00 each. The squad will receive $0.40 for each of the first 200 candy bars sold. For each of the next 300 sold, the squad will receive $0.50. For each additional candy bar sold, the squad will receive $0.60. How many candy bars must be squad sell to reach their goal of raising $350.00 ?", "choices": {"A": "350", "B": "584", "C": "667", "D": "700", "E": "875"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. The table below shows the age distribution of the student body at Memorial High School.What percent of the students are at Ieast 16 years old?", "choices": {"A": "34%", "B": "40%", "C": "50%", "D": "60%", "E": "66%"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. What percent of  is  ?", "choices": {"A": "22%", "B": "33%", "C": "50%", "D": "67%", "E": "200%"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. The sign below advertises a sale on coats. What is the sale price of a coat with a regular price of $84.00 ?", "choices": {"A": " $9.00", "B": "$21.00", "C": "$42.00", "D": "$63.00", "E": "$83.25"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. The ratio of a   side   of   square  A   to   the   length   of rectangle B is 2:3. The ratio of a side of square A to the width of rectangle B is  2: 1. What is  the  ratio of  the area of square A to the area of rectangle B ?", "choices": {"A": "2:1", "B": "3:1", "C": "3:2", "D": "4:1", "E": "4:3"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. In lntermediate Algebra class,  Ms.  Schimmack  makes the statement \"y varies directly as the product of w2 and x, and inversely as z3\" and asks her students to translate it into an equation. Which of the following equations, with k as the constant of proportionality, is a correct translation of Ms. Schimmack's statement?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": " y=kw2xz3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. In a certain isosceles triangle, the measure of each of the base angles is twice the measure of the vertex angle. What is the measure, in degrees, of each of the base angles?", "choices": {"A": "36\u00b0", "B": "60\u00b0", "C": "72\u00b0", "D": "120\u00b0", "E": "144\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. For a single production run, when n items are made and sold, a  company's\tprofit, P dollars, can  be modeled by P = n2 -300n - 100,000. What is  the smallest  number  of  items  that  must  be  made and  sold in order for the company not to lose money on the production run?", "choices": {"A": "150", "B": "200", "C": "300", "D": "350", "E": "500"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Use the following information to answer questions 32-34.Mousepads Galore is a company that produces computer mousepads. Cost is the  total  money spent to produce and sell the mousepads, and revenue is the total income generated by the sale of the mousepads. The graph below depicts  projections for the linear cost function,  C(x),  and the linear revenue function, R(x).During month of April, Mousepads Galore broke even    (did    not   gain,  or   lose   any   money)    when x' mousepads were  produced and sold. How many mousepads  did  the company  produce and sell during the month of April?", "choices": {"A": "10,000", "B": "12,000", "C": "14,000", "D": "15,000", "E": "30,000"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Use the following information to answer questions 32-34.Mousepads Galore is a company that produces computer mousepads. Cost is the  total  money spent to produce and sell the mousepads, and revenue is the total income generated by the sale of the mousepads. The graph below depicts  projections for the linear cost function,  C(x),  and the linear revenue function, R(x).The cost function shown in the graph for Mousepads Galore has 2 components : a fixed cost, plus a constant production cost per mousepad. Which or the following is the fixed cost?", "choices": {"A": "$0", "B": "$1,000", "C": "$10,000", "D": "$30,000", "E": "$100,000"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Use the following information to answer questions 32-34.Mousepads Galore is a company that produces computer mousepads. Cost is the  total  money spent to produce and sell the mousepads, and revenue is the total income generated by the sale of the mousepads. The graph below depicts  projections for the linear cost function,  C(x),  and the linear revenue function, R(x).Mousepads Galore sells each mousepad at the same p'rice, which is an integer number of dollar.According to the revenue function, what is the price of each of these mousepads?", "choices": {"A": "$3", "B": "$7", "C": "$10", "D": "$12", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Which of the following is a complete factorization of the expression 2x + 2xy + 6x2y ?", "choices": {"A": "2x(y + 3xy)", "B": "2x +2xy(1 + 3x)", "C": "2x(1 + y +4xy)", "D": "1 + y +3xy", "E": "2x(1 + y + 3xy)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Which of the following is an equation of the line that passes through the points (1, 3) and (-3, -13) in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": "x + y = 4", "B": "4x - y = 1", "C": " 5x - y = 2", "D": "6x - 2y = 8", "E": "7x - 2y = 5"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. A square has sides that are the same length as  the radius of a circle. If the circle has an area of36\u03c0 square units, how many units long is the perimeter of the square?", "choices": {"A": "18", "B": "24", "C": "36", "D": "72", "E": " 324"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. If the following system has a solution, what is the x-coordinate of the solution?                              3x + 6y = 52                                x + 6y = 24", "choices": {"A": "19", "B": "14", "C": "6", "D": "0", "E": "The system has no solution."}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. Use  the  following information  to  answer questions 39-41.In the figure below, B and C are on HD and G and F are on HE . The measurements given are in inches. Both BGFC anD CFED are trapezoids. The area, A, of a trapezoid is given by A = h(b1 + b2)\uff0cwhere h is the height and b1 and b2 are the lengths of the 2 parallel sides.What is the area of BGFC, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": "2,500", "B": "5,400", "C": "6,400", "D": "7,000", "E": "12,800"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Use  the  following information  to  answer questions 39-41.In the figure below, B and C are on HD and G and F are on HE . The measurements given are in inches. Both BGFC anD CFED are trapezoids. The area, A, of a trapezoid is given by A = h(b1 + b2)\uff0cwhere h is the height and b1 and b2 are the lengths of the 2 parallel sides.What is the length of BC , in inches?", "choices": {"A": "90", "B": "100", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Use  the  following information  to  answer questions 39-41.In the figure below, B and C are on HD and G and F are on HE . The measurements given are in inches. Both BGFC anD CFED are trapezoids. The area, A, of a trapezoid is given by A = h(b1 + b2)\uff0cwhere h is the height and b1 and b2 are the lengths of the 2 parallel sides.What is the radius, in inches, of the largest circle that can be drawn so that no point of the circle is outside CFED ?", "choices": {"A": "40", "B": "50", "C": "60", "D": "70", "E": "80"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. As shown in the figure below, an escape ramp leading from an emergency exit of an airplane is 35 feet long when fully extended and forms a 15\u00b0 angle with the level ground.Given the   trigonometric  approximations  in  the  table below, what is the height above the ground of the emergency exit, rounded to the nearest 0.1 foot?", "choices": {"A": "2.8", "B": "7.4", "C": "7.7", "D": "9.1", "E": "9.4"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. There are 10 equally spaced dots marked  on a circle. Kim chooses an integer, n, that  is  greater than  1. Beginning   at a randomly chosen  dot,  Kim goes around the circle clockwise and colors in  every nth dot. He continues going around and   around the circle coloring in every nth dot, counting each dot whether it is colored in or not, until he has colored in every  dot. Which of the  following could have bee Kim's integer n ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "4", "D": "5", "E": "6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. Consider the exponential equation  y = Cat, where  C and a are positive real constants and t is a positive real number.  The  value of  y decreases   as   the   value  of t increases if and only if which of  the  following statements about a is true?", "choices": {"A": "-1 \uff1c a", "B": "0 \uff1c a", "C": "0 \uff1c a \uff1c 1", "D": "1 \uff1c a \uff1c 2", "E": "1 \uff1c a"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. What is the distance, in coordinate units, between the points P(-2,-1) and Q( 1, 3) in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "3", "D": "5", "E": "7"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. During their morning jog in the park, Jean stops at a drinking fountain. Sula continues to jog and   gets 10 meters ahead of Jean. Sula is jogging at a constant rate of 2 meters per second , and Jean starts jogging at a constant rate of 2.4 meters per second to catch  up  to Sula. Which of  the following equations,  when solved for t, gives the number of seconds Jean will  take to catch up to Sula?", "choices": {"A": "2t + 10 = 2.4t", "B": "2t - 10 = 2.4t", "C": "", "D": "2t = 10", "E": "2.4t = 10"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. Which of  the following defines the solution set for the system of inequalities below?       x \u2264 64+2x \u2265 0", "choices": {"A": "x \u2265 -2", "B": "x \u2264 6", "C": " -8 \u2264 x \u2264 6", "D": "-2 \u2264 x \u2264 6", "E": "2 \u2264 x \u2264 6"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. At Brookfield High School, 55 seniors are enrolled in the sociology class and 40 seniors are enrolled in the drawing class. Of these seniors, 20 are enrolled in both the sociology  class and the  drawing  class.  How  many of the 120 seniors enrolled at Brookfield High School are NOT enrolled in either the sociology class or the drawing class?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "15", "C": "20", "D": "35", "E": "45"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. If two lines fo the standard (x, y) coordinate plane are perpendicular and the slope of one of the lines is  3, what is the slope of the other line?", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "-1", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "3"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. ln the standard (x, y) coordnate  plane, (12, 3) is half-way  between (2a, a + 3)  and (4a, a -  5). What is the value of a ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "6"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. How many 3-Ietter orderings, where no letter is repeated, can be made using the letters of the word GATORS?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "6", "C": "27", "D": "120", "E": "216"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. As shown in the (x, y, z) coordinate space below,  the cube with vertices A through H has edges that are 1 coordinate unit long. The coordinates  of  F  are (0,0,0), and H is on the positive y-axis. What are the coordinates of D ? ", "choices": {"A": "(0,1,1)", "B": "(0,,0)", "C": "(0,,1)", "D": "(0,,)", "E": "(1,1,1)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. Whenever x, y, and z are positive real numbers, which of\tthe\tfollowing\texpressions\tis equivalent to 2log3 x + log6 y -  log3 z ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. If 2 \u2264 x \u2264 5 and -4 \u2264 y \u2264 -3, what is the maximum value of   ?", "choices": {"A": "20", "B": "14", "C": "13", "D": "8", "E": "7"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. The measure of each interior angle of a regular n-sided polygon is . A regular pentagon is shown below. What is the measure of the designated angle?", "choices": {"A": " 108\u00b0", "B": "144\u00b0", "C": "198\u00b0", "D": "252\u00b0", "E": "188\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. Which of the following trigonometric functions has an amplitude of 2 ?(Note: The amplitude of a trigonometric function is the nonnegative difference between the maximum and minimum values  of  the function.)", "choices": {"A": "f(x) = 2 sin x", "B": "f(x) = 2 tan x", "C": " ", "D": "f(x) = cos 2x", "E": "f(x) =  cos x"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. Which of the following is an equivalent expression for r in terms of S and t whenever r, S, and t are all distinctand ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. In the figure below, lines l and m are parallel and  angle measures are as marked. If it can be determined, what is the value of x ?", "choices": {"A": "35", "B": "45", "C": "65", "D": "80", "E": "Cannot be determined  from the given information"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. In  the triangle below, where  the  2 given  side lengths are expressed in feet, what is the value of b ?", "choices": {"A": "3 cos 20\u00b0", "B": "3 sin 20\u00b0", "C": "3 tan 20\u00b0", "D": "3 sin 70\u00b0", "E": " 3 tan 70\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. An  angle  in  standard   position   in the standard (x, y) coordinate  plane has its  vertex  at the  origin and its initial side on the positive x-axis, If the measure of an angle in standard  position  is 1,573\u00b0\uff0cit has  the  same terminal side as an angle of each of the following measures EXCEPT:", "choices": {"A": "-587\u00b0", "B": "-227\u00b0", "C": "133\u00b0", "D": "493\u00b0", "E": "573\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}]}